French nationality Currently based in London, United Kingdom

thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Tech Lead / Senior Software Engineer

Profile

I am a software engineer with 15 years of experience in building tech solutions across several industries with a strong entrepreneurial focus. I am equally comfortable with hands-on delivery (i.e. writing code) and managing engineering teams (i.e. helping other developers writing code). I help organisations to embrace new ranges of technologies to solve challenging real-world problems, and launch successful products that customers love.

Work experience

Lead Software Engineer (contract based) for a global publishing house

Conde Nast, London, United Kingdom – Since March 2021 (www.condenast.com)

Building and Improving a content migration tool for Conde Nast's in-house engineering teams.

Working for a software consultancy (YLD) on improving a set of APIs and tools automating content migration for 50 publications to a new tech stack. Writing code and delivering new features. Code reviews. 3rd level support.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Node.is, TypeScript, Express, React, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, CircleCl, Jenkins, OAuth / Okta SSO

Senior Backend Engineer (contract based) for a content marketing agency

Progressive Content, London, United Kingdom – Sept. 2020 to Feb. 2021 (progressivecontent.com)

Building a microservices backend for the content marketing CMS of a UK based banking client.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Serverless, TypeScript, GraphQL, Node.js, Docker, Jenkins, AWS, Elasticsearch.

Tech Advisor / CTO for an early-stage startup, building interactive education solutions for kids. London, United Kingdom - February to July 2020

The startup generator Antler invited me to work on an early-stage tech-related business model.

Lead Backend Engineer (contract based) for a software consultancy

AND Digital, London, United Kingdom – July 2019 to January 2020 (www.and.digital)

Leading a development team part of a cloud transformation project for a UK insurance client.

Writing code and delivering new features for an end-user web application. Managing integration with 3rd party back-office services (both REST and SOAP). Refining user stories. Code reviews. Agile (SCRUM) delivery.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Serverless, TypeScript, Express, Node.js, React, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, REST, SOAP.

Head of Engineering for a health-tech startup

Skin Analytics, London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (www.skin-analytics.com)

 \rightarrow Responsible for clients, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures

Managing applications, cloud infrastructure and releases. Defining roadmaps and priorities and scoping new requirements. Writing code. Hiring and leading technical team (8 members between London and Poland). Day to day management, code reviews and testing. Delivered a Software as a Medical Device commercial API.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, React, React Native, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible.

Technical Lead (contract based) for an international online media publishing group

Jamie Oliver, London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (www.jamieoliver.com)

Scoping and delivering migration from a legacy SOAP CRM to a micro-services cloud-based (AWS) architecture.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

Mentor, since 2017

 \rightarrow Mentoring for the tech lead curriculum for the primary french online education platform <u>Open Classrooms</u> **Team Leader / Technology Manager** for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components

 Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local startups among the most repressive regimes. Leading on delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

 Overseeing the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 5 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Focus on scalability & security.
- → <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, PHP (Laravel), WordPress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

Web Application Engineer for an international NGO

Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - Mar. 2009 to Mar. 2015 (www.internews.org)

- → Online freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

 Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Deployment and monitoring of secure hosting & video platforms. Facilitating training & trainers: website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).
- → <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, WordPress, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Vagrant, Nginx, Linux administration

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (www.hellotipi.com)

→ <u>Technology</u>: MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg, Debian, Linux administration

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in the two major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs.

Junior Software Engineer for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course support creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (<u>www.esiea.fr</u>)

ightarrow Graduated with first class honours.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner

Hobbies

Collecting records (LPs), mostly nerdy noisy music. <u>Photography</u> (film and digital). Part of the media team of a <u>non-league fan-owned football club</u> in East London.